In the beginning...
むかしむかし
there was only ocean...
海だけの世界に
until the mother island emerged.
母なる大地が現れた
Te Fiti.
テフィティ
Her heart held the greatest power ever known.
彼女の心臓には 偉大な力があった
It could create life itself.
命を生む力
And Te Fiti shared it with the world.
世界に広がった
But in time...
しかしある時
some began to seek Te Fiti's heart.
彼女の心臓を狙う者がいた
They believed if they could possess it...
彼女の心臓
the great power of creation would be theirs.
生命の源を 手に入れようと考えた
And one day...
ある日
the most daring of them all...
大胆な者が
voyaged across the vast ocean to take it.
盗みに来た
He was a demigod of the wind and sea.
風と海の半神
He was a warrior.
戦士でもあった
A trickster.
いたずらで
A shapeshifter who could change form...
変身する事が出来た
with the power of his magical fish hook.
魔法の釣り針を使った
And his name...
彼の名は
was Maui.
マウイ
But without her heart, Te Fiti began to crumble...
心臓を失くした テフィティは砕け散り
giving birth to a terrible darkness.
恐ろしい闇となった
Maui tried to escape...
マウイは逃げたが 戦わねば ならなかった
but was confronted by another who sought the heart.
狙う者は他にもいた... それは
Te Kā!
テカー
A demon of earth and fire.
地と火の神
Maui was struck from the sky...
マウイは 叩き落され
never to be seen again.
姿を消した
And his magical fish hook and the heart of Te Fiti...
心臓と 釣り針は
were lost to the sea.
海に消えた
Where, even now...
そして
1,000 years later...
千年が経った今でも
Te Kā and the demons of the deep...
テカーと テフィティは
still hunt for the heart.
心臓をさがしている
Hiding in a darkness that will continue to spread...
闇は隠れて拡がり
chasing away our fish...
魚を追い払い
draining the life from island after island...
島から島へ生命力を奪った
until every one of us is devoured...
一人残らず
by the bloodthirsty jaws...
血みどろの顎に喰われ
of inescapable death!
死んでしまうのだ
But one day...
いつの日かきっと
the heart will be found...
心臓が見つかる
by someone who will journey beyond our reef...
珊瑚礁を越える者が現れ
find Maui...
マウイを見つけ
deliver him across the great ocean...
大海原を越えて彼を運び
to restore Te Fiti's heart...
テフィティに心臓を返し
and save us all.
我らを救ってくれる...
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Thank you, Mother. That's enough.
おいおい 母さん それで充分
Papa.
パパ
No one goes outside the reef.
誰も珊瑚礁の向こうに行かない
We are safe here. There is no darkness.
ここは安全 闇もない
There are no monsters.
怪物もいない
Monsters!
怪物！
- There's no monsters, no monsters... - It's the darkness!
怪物はいないよ 暗いだけだよ
No, there is nothing beyond our reef, but storms and rough seas.
珊瑚礁の向こうは何にもない 嵐と 荒れ海だけ
I'm gonna throw up.
吐きそう！
As long as we stay on our very safe island...
島にいれば安全
...we'll be fine.
大丈夫だよ
The legends are true.
伝説は本物
Someone will have to go.
誰かが行かねば
Mother, Motunui is paradise.
母さん モトゥニは天国
Who would want to go anywhere else?
出て行きたい人は いない
Shoo,shoo!
しっ しっ
Moana!
モアナ！
There you are, Moana. What are you doing? You scared me.
モアナ何してる おどかさないでくれ
What? I wanna's go back.
あっちに行きたい
I know, I know. But you don't go out there.
よしよし あっちに行かないで
It's dangerous.
危ないんだ
Moana, come on.
モアナ こっちへおいで
Let's go back to the village.
村へ帰ろう
You are the next great chief of our people.
お前は次の村長
And you will do wondrous things, my little minnow.
お前は立派な事するのよ おちびちゃん
Oh, yes. But first, you must learn where you're meant to be.
最初に お前の場所を学ぼう
Moana
モアナ
Make way, make way
道をあけて
Moana, it's time you knew
モアナ 知る時だよ
The village of Motunui is all you need
モツゥニの村がすべて
The dancers are practicing
人は踊る
They dance to an ancient song
いにしえの歌を踊る
Who needs a new song This old one's all we need
新しい歌は要らない いにしえの歌があれば
This tradition is our mission
伝統を守ろう
And Moana, there's so much to do
モアナ 大忙しだよ
Don't trip on the taro root
タロイモで転ばないで
That's all you need
それでいい
We share everything we make
作ったら 分け合い
We joke and we weave our baskets
ふざけたり カゴを編んだり
The fishermen come back from the sea
漁師は海から帰る
I wanna see
見たいー
Don't walk away
逃げないで
Moana, stay on the ground now
モアナ しっかりと根付いて
Our people will need a chief
みんなは村長が必要
- And there you are - There you are
ほらね
There comes a day
その日が来た
When you're gonna look around And realize happiness is
まわりを見ればわかる しあわせは
Where you are
君がいる場所にある
Consider the coconut
ココナッツを見て
- The what - Consider its tree
ヤシの木を見て
We use each part of the coconut It's all we need
ココナッツをすべて使う それで充分
We make our nets from the fibers
ツタで アミを作るよ
The water is sweet inside
中身は甘く
We use the leaves to build fires We cook up the meat inside
葉を燃やして料理する
Consider the coconuts
ココナッツを見て
The trunks and the leaves
ヤシの木と ヤシの葉
The island gives us what we need
必要な物は島にある
And no one leaves
誰も去らない
That's right, we stay
ここにいよう
We're safe and we're well-provided
安全で豊か
And when we look to the future
未来を見よう
There you are
ほらね
You'll be okay
心配ない
In time you'll learn just as I did
やがて君も学ぶ 僕が学んだ様に
You must find happiness right where you are
君がいる場所で しあわせを見つけて
I like to dance with the water The undertow and the waves
海で踊るのが好き 波が行ったり来たり
The water is mischievous Ha! I like how it misbehaves
海はいたずら 私はそれが好き
The village may think I'm crazy Or say that I drift too far
私は変わり者 遠くへ流されしまった
But once you know what you like Well, there you are
好きな事を 良く知れば ほらね
You are your father's daughter Stubbornness and pride
お前は父さんの娘 強くて誇り高い
Mind what he says but remember You may hear a voice inside
父さんの話を良くお聞き でも 心の声も聞きなさい
And if the voice starts to whisper To follow the farthest star
もし心の声がささやいたら 遠くの星を追いなさい
Moana, that voice inside is who you are
モアナ 心の声は あなた自身だから
- Uh-huh. - Dad!
こらこら パパ！
I was only looking at the boats. I wasn't gonna get on 'em.
船を見てただけ 乗ろうとしてない
Come on. There's something I need to show you.
おいで 見せたいものがある
I've wanted to bring you here from the moment you opened your eyes.
お前が生まれた時から ここに連れて来たかった
This is a sacred place.
聖なる場所だよ
A place of chiefs.
村長の場所
There will come a time...
きっと来る
when you will stand on this peak and place a stone on this mountain.
お前が頂上に立ち 石を置く時が
Like I did. Like my father did.
お前の父さんも 父さんの父さんも
And his father, and every chief that has ever been.
お爺さんの父さんも みんなそうしてきた
And on that day...
お前が
when you add your stone...
石を置く時は
you will raise this whole island higher.
島はもっと 豊かになる
You are the future of our people, Moana.
お前はみんなの 未来なんだ モアナ
And they are not out there.
みんなは よそでなく
They are right here.
ここにいる
It's time to be who they need you to be.
みんな君が必要 その時が来たんだ
- We make our nets from the fibers - We weave our nets from the fibers
ツタでアミを作るよ
- The water is sweet inside - A real tasty treat inside
中身は甘く とてもおいしい
- We use the leaves to build fires - We sing these songs in our choirs
ヤシの葉で火を起こそう 歌をうたおう
- To cook up the meat inside - We have mouths to feed inside
ヤシの実を料理して食べよう
- The village believes in us - That's right
みんな信じている それが一番だと
The village believes
みんな信じている
The island gives us what we need
島にはすべてがある
And no one leaves
誰も去らない
So here I'll stay
ここにいる
My home, my people beside me And when I think of tomorrow
明日も 家族とみんなは
There we are
そこにいる
I'll lead the way
先を行くわ
I'll have my people to guide me
みんな私を導いて
We'll build our future together
一緒に未来を作ろう
Where we are
私たちの場所で
'Cause every path leads ya back to
道は戻る
Where you are
あなたがいる場所に
You can find happiness right
君はしあわせを見つける
Where you are
君がいる場所で
しあわせは 君がいる場所にある
And every storm, this roof leaks, no matter how many fronds I add.
嵐でいつも 雨漏り たくさん葉を使ったのに
Fixed!
直したわ！
Not the fronds.
葉じゃない
- Wind shifted the post. - Ah!
風で柱が ずれたのよ
Mmm! That's good pork!
おいしい豚肉
Oh! I didn't mean... I wasn't...
違うのよ...えっと
What? They're calling me, so I gotta... Bye!
誰か呼んでる 行かなくちゃ
Ow! Ow! Ow!
痛い！
You're doing great.
その調子
Is it done yet?
終わった？
So close.
あとちょっと
I'm curious about that chicken eating the rock.
ニワトリが 石を食べておる
He seems to lack the basic intelligence required for pretty much everything.
生きる知恵がないな
Should we maybe just cook him?
焼いてやろうか
Sometimes our strengths lie beneath the surface.
見た目で 良さはわからない
Far beneath in some cases.
やっぱり わからないわね
But I'm sure there's more to Heihei
でも ヘイヘイは
than meets the eye.
見た目よりも もっと良いはず
It's the harvest.
収穫したばかり
This morning, I was husking the coconuts and...
今朝ココナツの皮をむいたら
Well...
いたんでる
we should clear the diseased trees and we will start a new grove.
病気の木を切って 新しい果樹園を作って
There.
あそこに
Thanks, Moana.
ありがとう モアナ
She's doing great.
彼女は 大したものね
This suits you.
お前らしい
Chief?
村長
There's something you need to see.
見てほしい事が
Our traps in the east lagoon...
しかけに
they're pulling up less and less fish.
魚がかからない
Then we'll rotate the fishing grounds.
場所を変えて
Uh, we have. There's no fish.
変えた 魚がいないんだ
Oh. Then we'll fish the far side of the island.
もっと島から離れた場所は
We tried.
試したよ
The windward side.
風上は？
And the leeward side, the shallows, the channel.
風下も 浅瀬も  珊瑚礁の切れ目も
We've tried the whole lagoon.
みんな試した
They're just gone.
いなくなった
Have you tried using a different bait?
別のエサはどう
I don't think it's the bait.
エサのせいじゃない
There's no fish.
本当にいなくなったんだ
It seems like it's getting worse and worse.
もっと悪い事が起こりそうだ
Of course, I understand you have reason for concern.
何とかしないと
I will talk to the council. I'm sure we...
みんなと話し合おう
What if we fish beyond the reef?
珊瑚礁の外に 魚がいるんじゃない？
No one goes beyond the reef.
珊瑚礁の外には 誰も行かない
I know. But if there are no fish in the lagoon...
知ってる でも魚がいないのなら
- Moana. - And there's a whole ocean.
海はこんなに大きいのに
We have one rule.
掟があるんだよ
An old rule, when there were fish.
古い掟だわ 魚がいるかもしれない
- A rule that keeps us safe... - But Dad, I...
掟はみんなを守っている でもパパ
...instead of endangering our people so you can run right back to the water.
みんなを危険な目にあわせないでくれ 海ならいつでも行けるだろう
Every time I think you're past this...
いつもお前が心配なんだ
No one goes beyond the reef!
珊瑚礁の向こうには 行かないでくれよ
Well, it's not like you said it in front of your dad.
父さんに話した事と 少し違うわね
Standing on a boat.
船の上で
I didn't say go beyond the reef, because I want to be on the ocean.
珊瑚礁の外とは言ってない 海の上にいたいだけ
But you still do.
ほらまた言ってる
- He's hard on you because... - Because he doesn't get me.
父さんが厳しいのは... 私の事わかってない
Because he was you.
お父さんはあなたと 同じだったの
Drawn to the ocean.
海に憧れていた
Down by the shore.
海辺から
He took a canoe, Moana.
彼はカヌーに乗った
He crossed the reef...
珊瑚礁の向こうに行った
and found an unforgiving sea.
海の厳しさを知った
Waves like mountains.
山のような波
His best friend begged to be on that boat.
親友は 船にしがみついたけど
Your dad couldn't save him.
父さんは彼を助けられなかった
He's hoping he can save you.
父さんは あなたを守りたいの
Sometimes...
ときには
who we wish we were, what we wish we could do...
成りたい人に成れず やりたい事が
it's just not meant to be.
できないの
I've been staring at the edge of the water
海辺をずっと見てた
Long as I can remember
考えても
Never really knowing why
わからない
I wish I could be the perfect daughter
ふさわしい娘に なれたらいいのに
But I come back to the water
心は海に戻ってしまう
No matter how hard I try
どんなに頑張っても
Every turn I take Every trail I track
なん度も どの道も 試した
Every path I make Every road leads back
戻ってしまう
To the place I know Where I cannot go
行けないと知っている所へ
Where I long to be
どうしても行きたい
See the line where the sky meets the sea
空と海が出会う場所
It calls me
海が私を呼ぶ
And no one knows
誰も知らない
How far it goes
海はどんなに深いの遠いのか
If the wind in my sail on the sea Stays behind me
私の帆に海風が吹いたら
One day I'll know
いつかわかる
If I go, there's just no telling how far I'll go
どこまで遠くに行けるのか
I know everybody on this island
私は知っている 島のみんなは
Seems so happy on this island
とてもしあわせ
Everything is by design
みんなには目的がある
I know everybody on this island
知っているの 島のみんなには
Has a role on this island
役目がある
So maybe I can roll with mine
だから私も役目を果たす
I can lead with pride I can make us strong
誇りを持って先頭に立ち みんなをもっと強くする
I'll be satisfied If I play along
うまくやれば 私は満足するはず
But the voice inside Sings a different song
でも心の中には別の歌が
What is wrong with me
私はいったい どうしてしまったの
See the light as it shines on the sea
海の中で輝いている
It's blinding
まばゆく光る
But no one knows
誰も知らない
How deep it goes
どんなに深くても
And it seems like it's calling out to me
私を呼んでいる気がする
So come find me
私を見つけに来て
And let me know
教えて
What's beyond that line Will I cross that line
向こうに何があるのか
The line where the sky meets the sea
空と海が出会う場所
It calls me
私を呼ぶの
And no one knows
みんなは知らない
How far it goes
海はどんなに深いのか
If the wind in my sail on the sea stays behind me
私の帆に海風が吹いたら
One day I'll know
いつかわかる
How far I'll go
どのくらい遠くまで行けるのか
Whoa.
わあ
We're okay, Pua.
大丈夫 プア
I can do this.
できるわ
There's more fish beyond the reef.
珊瑚礁の向こうに もっと魚がいるはず
There's more beyond the reef.
向こうにもっと いるはず
Not so bad.
やれそう
Pua!
プア！
Whatever just happened...
何でも
blame it on the pig.
豚のせい
Gramma.
お婆さん
Are you gonna tell Dad?
お父さんに言うの？
I'm his mom. I don't have to tell him anything.
私は彼の母親 全てを話す必要はない
He was right.
お父さんは正しかった
About going out there.
いけないって
It's time to put my stone on the mountain.
山に石を置く時なのね
Okay. Well, then, head on back.
そうかい それなら行っておいで
Put that stone up there.
石を置いてくるがいい
Why aren't you trying to talk me out of it?
言いたい事があるの？
You said that's what you wanted.
石を置くのが望みだろう
It is.
そうよ
When I die...
私が死んだら
I'm going to come back as one of these.
マンタになって 戻って来る
Or I chose the wrong tattoo.
そうでなければ 入れ墨を間違えた
Why are you acting weird?
なに変なこと言ってるの
I'm the village crazy lady. That's my job.
私は村の変人さ それが私の仕事
If there's something you want to tell me, just tell me!
言いたい事があるなら ちゃんと言って
Is there something you wanna tell me?
話したい事があるの？
Is there something you want to hear?
知りたい事があるのかい
You've been told all our people's stories...
伝説をすべて 教わったね
but one.
ひとつ以外
What is this place?
ここはどこ？
Do you really think our ancestors stayed within the reef?
ご先祖様はずっと珊瑚礁に いたって思うのかい
Ooh!
ほほう
What's in there?
中に何があるの？
The answer to the question you keep asking yourself.
答えだよ お前がずっと知りたかった
Who are you meant to be?
本当はいったい誰なのか
Go inside...
中へ入って
bang the drum...
ドラムを叩け
and find out.
見つけなさい
Whoa.
わあ
Oh.
ああ
Bang the drum.
ドラムを叩け
We read the wind and the sky
我らは風と空を読む
When the sun is high
太陽が登る時
We sail the length of the seas
海の果てまで航海する
On the ocean breeze
海がそよぐ時
At night we name every star
星の名前はすべて知っている
We know where we are
どこにいても場所がわかる
We know who we are Who we are
We set a course to find
航路を定め
A brand new island everywhere we roam
新しい島を見つける 我らはさすらう
We keep our island in our mind
島の場所を知っている
And when it's time to find home
帰る時は
We know the way
道がわかる
We are explorers reading every sign
我らは探検家 どんなサインも読み取る
We tell the stories of our elders In a never-ending chain
果てしない先祖の 伝説を語る
We know the way
道がわかる
We were voyagers.
私達は航海者
We were voyagers!
航海者だったの
We were voyagers! We were voyagers!
私達は 航海者だった
We were voyagers!
航海者だったの！
Why'd we stop?
どうして 航海をやめたの？
Maui.
マウイさ
When he stole from the mother island, darkness fell.
母なる大地から盗まれた時 闇が訪れた
Te Kā awoke.
テカーは目覚めた
Monsters lurked and boats stopped coming back.
怪物は待ち伏せし 船は戻らなかった
To protect our people, the ancient chiefs forbid voyaging...
民を守るため 村長達は航海を禁じた
and now we have forgotten who we are.
そして自分たちが誰なのか ついに忘れてしまった
And the darkness has continued to spread...
闇は広がり続け
chasing away our fish...
魚がいなくなった
draining the life...
生命力は 失われている
from island after island.
島から島へ
Our island.
私達の島も
But, one day...
しかし いつの日か
someone will journey beyond our reef, find Maui...
誰かが珊瑚礁を越え マウイを見つける
deliver him across the great ocean...
海を越え彼を運び
to restore the heart of Te Fiti.
テフィティの心臓を 返すのだ
I was there that day.
あの日私はそこにいた
The ocean chose you.
海がお前を選んだ
I thought it was a dream.
夢だと思ってた
Nope!
こら
Our ancestors believed Maui lies there...
先祖は 信じていた
at the bottom of his hook.
マウイは 釣り針の下にいると
Follow it, and you will find him.
そこへ行きなさい そして彼を見つけて
But why would it choose me?
なぜ海は 私を選んだの？
I don't even know how to make it past the reef.
珊瑚礁の向こうに 行くこともできないのに
But I know who does!
でも 行ける人がいる
The crops are turning black.
作物が 黒くなった
What about the fish?
魚はどうなんだい
This is happening all over the island.
島中で起きている
- Please, please settle down. - What are you going to do?
落ち着いて考えよう
We will dig new fields. We will find a way to...
新しく土地を...
We can stop the darkness! Save our island!
闇は止められる 島を守ろう
There's a cavern of boats.
船の洞窟があるの
Huge canoes.
巨大なカヌーも
We can take them, find Maui, make him restore the heart.
マウイを見つけ心臓を返すの
We were voyagers. We can voyage again!
私たちは航海者なのよ また航海に出るの！
You told me to help our people.
お父さんが みんなを助けなさいって
This is how we help our people.
みんなを助ける方法なの
Dad?
お父さん？
What are you doing?
何するの
I should've burned those boats a long time ago!
昔のうちに船を 燃やしておけば良かった
No! Don't!
やめて
We have to find Maui. We have to restore the heart!
マウイを見つけないと 心臓を返さないと
There is no heart!
心臓なんかじゃない
This is just a rock!
ただの石だ
No!
やめて
Chief! It's your mother!
村長！ お母様が
Mother...
母さん
What can be done?
何か出来ることは...
Go.
行っておいで
Gramma.
お婆さん
Go.
お行きなさい
Not now. I can't.
今はだめ できない
You must!
お行き
The ocean chose you.
海がお前を 選んだのだから
Follow the fish hook.
釣り針に向かって 行くのだよ
Gramma...
お婆さん
And when you find Maui...
マウイを見つけたら
you grab him by the ear. You say...
耳をつかんで言うの
"I am Moana of Motunui.
私はモトゥヌイのモアナ
"You will board my boat...
私の船に乗り
"sail across the sea...
海を越え
"and restore the heart of Te Fiti."
テフィティの心臓を 返しなさい
I can't leave you.
置いてなんか行けない
There is nowhere you could go that I won't be with you.
お前が行く場所には 私はいつも一緒
Go!
お行き
There's a line where the sky meets the sea
空と海が出会う場所
And it calls me
私を呼んでいる
But no one knows
誰も知らない
How far it goes
海の大きさを
All that time wondering where I need to be is behind me
いつも不思議に思った 私がいるべき所を後にして
I'm on my own
私ひとりで行く
To worlds unknown
知らない世界へ
Every turn I take Every trail I track
いつも同じ道をたどる
Is a choice I make
心に決めた
Now I can't turn back from the great unknown
もう戻れない 未知の世界へ
Where I go alone Where I long to be
ひとりで行く どうしても行きたかった所
See her light up the night in the sea
海が夜を照らし
She calls me
海が私を呼ぶ
And yes, I know
私にはわかる
That I can go
私なら行ける
There's a moon in the sky And the wind is behind me
空には月 風が私を押す
Soon I'll know
すぐにわかる
How far I'll go
どんなに遠くへ行けるのか
I am Moana of Motunui. You will board my boat...
私はモトゥヌイのモアナ 私の船に乗って
sail across the sea and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
海を越えテフィティの 心臓を返しなさい
I am Moana...
私はモアナ
of Motu...
モトゥ...
...nui.
ヌイの...
Heihei?
ヘイヘイ？
It's okay. You're all right.
大丈夫 心配ないわ
See?
ね？
There we go. Nice water.
ほら きれいな海でしょ
The ocean is a friend of mine.
海は私の友達
Heihei?
ヘイヘイ？
Heihei!
ヘイヘイ！
Sta)'-
そこにいて
Okay. Next stop, Maui.
次はマウイよ
I am Moana of Motunui.
私はモトゥヌイのモアナ
You will board my boat...
私の船に乗って...
sail... across the sea...
海を... 越え...
and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
テフィティの心臓を 返しなさい
I am Moana of Motu...
私はモトゥヌイの...
Board my boat!
私の船に乗りなさい！
Oh, no.
あらいや
No,no,no!
ちょっと！
Ocean...
ねえ海さん
can I get a little help?
手伝ってくれる？
No, no.
待って
Please.
お願い
Come on!
そうじゃないの
Help me!
助けて！
Please!
お願い！
Whew!
ふう
Um...
うーん
What?
何よ！
I said help me!
助けてって言ったのに
And wrecking my boat?
船を壊した
Not helping!
助けてくれないのね
Fish pee in you all day!
お魚さんは毎日 おしっこしてるわ
So...
だから...
Maui?
マウイ？
Maui!
マウイ
Maui, demigod of the wind and sea...
マウイ 風と海の半神...
I am Moana of Motunui.
私はモトゥヌイのモアナ
You will board my boat.
私の船に乗りなさい
No. You will board my boat.
違うわ 私の船に乗りなさい
Yeah. I am Moana of Motunui.
そうよ 私はモトゥヌイのモアナ
You will board my...
私の船に...
Boat! A boat!
船だ
The gods have given me a...
神様がくれたんだ...
Maui, shapeshifter...
マウイ 変身できる...
demigod of the wind and sea...
風と海の半神
- I am Moana of... - Hero of men.
私はモアナ... 英雄さ！
What?
えっ？
It's actually, Maui, shapeshifter, demigod of the wind and sea...
そうさマウイだ 変身できる風と海の半神...
hero of men.
英雄さ
I interrupted. From the top. Hero of men. Go.
邪魔したな 僕は英雄  続けて
I am...
私は...
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
ちょっと待った
And women. Men and women.
女だろ  男と女
Both. All.
ただそれだけ
Not a guy, girl thing.
恋愛はなし
You know, Maui is a hero to all.
知ってるか マウイはみんなの英雄
You're doing great.
頑張ったな
What? No! I'm here to...
えっ?違うわ！ ここに来たのは...
Of course.
もちろん
Yes, yes, yes.
そうそう
Maui always has time for his fans.
マウイにはいつも ファンがいる
When you use a bird to write with...
書く時に鳥を使うと...
it's called tweeting.
ツイッターって言うんだ
I know, not every day you get a chance to meet your hero.
英雄に会えるチャンスは そうそうない
You are not my hero.
あなたは私の英雄じゃない
And I'm not here so you can sign my oar!
サインをもらいに来たんじゃない
I'm here 'cause you stole the heart of Te Fiti!
あなたがテフィティの心臓を 盗んだから来たの
And you will board my boat...
あなたは私の船に乗って...
and sail across the sea and put it back!
心臓を返しなさい
Um...
ふーむ...
Yeah, it almost sounded like you don't like me...
僕が嫌い？
which is impossible because...
そんなはずはない なぜって
I got stuck here for 1,000 years...
千年も ここにいた
trying to get the heart as a gift for you mortals.
人間に心臓を プレゼントしようと思った
So you could have the power to create life itself.
人間が 命を生む力を手に入れられるように
Yeah. So, what I believe you were trying to say...
お前が言いたかった事は
is "thank you."
ありがとう
-"Thank you?" - You're welcome.
ありがとう? どういたしまして
What? No, no, no!
えっ違うわ
I didn't... I wasn't...
そうじゃなくて...
Why would I ever say that?
そんなこと なぜ言う必要がある?
Okay, Okay
よしよし
I see what's happening Yeah
わかってる
You're face to face with greatness and it's strange
偉大な者に会うと 変な気分
You don't even know how you feel
どう感じればいいのか わからないんだろ
It's adorable
かわいいな
Well it's nice to see that humans never change
人間は変わらない
Open your eyes Let's begin
目を開けて 始めよう
Yes, it's really me
僕はまさに
It's Maui Breathe it in
マウイさ 息を吸って
I know it's a lot
わかってる
The hair The bod
髪と体
When you're staring at a demigod
見つめられると
What can I say except
言うしかない
You're welcome
どういたしまして
For the tides, the sun, the sky
波も太陽も空も 僕のおかげ
Hey, it's okay, it's okay
気にしないで
You're welcome
どういたしまして
I'm just an ordinary demiguy Hey!
僕はただの半神
What has two thumbs and pulled up the sky
誰の親指で 空を押したの
When you were waddling yay high?
よちよち歩きの人間が イエーイしてる時
This guy
この僕
When the nights got cold Who stole you fire from down below?
寒い夜 火を 盗んで来たのは誰
You're looking at him yo
彼を見ろ
Oh also I lassoed the sun
投げ縄で 太陽をつかまえた
You're welcome
どういたしまして
To stretch your days and bring you fun
昼を伸ばした 楽しいだろ
Also I harnessed the breeze
風も使えるだろ
You're welcome
どういたしまして
To fill your sails and shake your trees
帆が使えるだろ 木を揺らせるだろ
So what can I say except You're welcome
だから こう言うしかない どういたしまして
For the islands I pulled from the sea
海から島を作ったぞ
There's no need to pray It's okay
祈らなくていいさ 要らないよ
You're welcome
どういたしまして
Ha I guess it's just my way of being me
僕であるための やり方
You're welcome
どういたしまして
Well come to think of it
考えてみたら
Kid, honestly I could go on and on
続けても良かったけどね
I could explain every natural phenomenon
自然を あやつる事を
The tide, the grass, the ground Oh that was Maui just messing around
潮 草 大地 マウイの仕業さ
I killed an eel I buried its guts
ウナギを殺して埋めたら
Sprouted a tree Now you got coconuts
木の芽が出て ココナッツが出来た
What's the lesson? What is the take away?
教訓は何？何がわかった？
Don't mess with Maui when he's on a breakaway
マウイが自由な時には かかわるな
And the tapestry here on my skin ls a map of the victories I win
皮膚の入れ墨は 勝利の地図
Look where I've been I make everything happen
やった事が書いてある
Look at that Mean Mini-Maui just tickety tappin'
盗み聞きの ミニ・マウイ
Ha ha Ha ha
ハ ハ ハ ハ
Ha ha Hey
ハ ハ ヘイ
Well anyway let me say You're welcome
とにかく言わせて どういたしまして
You're welcome
どういたしまして
For the wonderful world you know
素晴らしい世界に 感謝して
Hey, it's okay, it's okay You're welcome
気にしないで どういたしまして
You're welcome
どういたしまして
Well come to think of it I gotta go
考えて見たら もう行かないと
Hey it's your day to say You're welcome
今日はお前が言う番さ "どういたしまして"って
You're welcome
"どういたしまして"って
'Cause I'm gonna need that boat
僕は船が必要
I'm sailing away away You're welcome
船に乗って行っちゃうよ どういたしまして
You're welcome
どういたしまして
'Cause Maui can do everything but float
マウイは何でもできる 浮かないだけ
- You're welcome - You're welcome
どういたしまして どういたしまして
Huh?
え？
And thank you!
ありがとな
Hey!
ちょっと！
Let me out! You lying, slimy son of a...
ここから出して うそつき
You're welcome
どういたしまして
You're so welcome.
本当に どういたしまして
No. I'm not going to Te Fiti with some kid.
テフィティの所に行かない 子供とは
I'm going to get my hook.
釣り針を取りに行こう
You have yours and I'm not Maui without mine.
お前は自分のがあるだろ ないと僕はマウイじゃないんだ
Okay, talk to the back.
背中と話してろ
Boat snack.
船の おやつ
Good riddance, you filthy pile of pebbles.
うまく逃げ出せた がれきの山から
Oh, no, no, no. Don't look at me like that.
そんな目で 見ないでくれ ミニマウイ
It's a beautiful cave. She's gonna love it.
きれいな洞窟さ 彼女は気に入る
And I'm going to love you in ma belly.
お前も気にいる お腹の中でな
Now, let's fatten you up, drumstick.
太らせよう やせっぽっち
I could watch that all day.
見ていたかったけど
Okay. Enjoy the island.
島を楽しめ
Maui, out.
マウイ出発
No! Stop!
行かないで
Hey! You have to put back the heart!
心臓を返しに行きなさい
Did not see that coming.
そう来るとは思わなかった
I am Moana of Motunui.
私はモアナ モトゥヌイの
This is my canoe...
これは私の船...
and you will journey to...
あなたは海を越え...
All right, get over it. We gotta move.
よしやっつけた 行こう
And she's back.
また戻った
I am Moana of Motunui...
私はモアナ モトゥヌイの...
It was Moana, right?
モアナだろ
Yes.
そうよ
And you will restore the heart!
あなたは 心臓を返すの
All right. I'm out.
僕は降りた
Oh, come on!
何なんだよ
What is your problem?
何か問題ある？
Are you afraid of it?
これが怖いの？
No! No.
ちがう
I'm not afraid.
怖いんじゃない
Stay out of it or you're sleeping in my armpit.
口出しするなミニマウイ
You, stop it.
やめるんだ
That is not a heart. It is a curse.
心臓なんかじゃない 呪いだぞ
The second I took it, I got blasted outta the sky...
取った途端 吹き飛ばされた
and I lost my hook.
釣り針もなくした
Get it away from me.
離れろ
Get this away?
離れたいの？
Hey, hey, hey! I'm a demigod, okay?
おいこら 僕は半神なんだぞ
Stop that. I will smite you!
やめてくれ 殴るぞ
You wanna get smote?
殴られたいのか?
Smotten?
えーと殴られ...たいのか？
Listen, that thing doesn't give you power to create life...
命を生む力なんかない
it's a homing beacon of death.
追いかけてくる死だ
If you don't put it away, bad things are gonna come for it.
しまわないと悪い事が起こる
Come for this? The heart?
この心臓で？
You mean this heart right here?
これが怖いの？
Don't, you can't raise your voice like that!
やめろ そんなに大声出すな
Come and get it!
取りに来なさい
You are gonna get us killed!
死ぬんだぞ
No, I'm gonna get us to Te Fiti, so you can put it back.
いいえテフィティの所に行くわ あなたが返して
Thank you.
ありがと
You're welcome.
どういたしまして
Kakamora.
カカモラ
Kaka-what?
カカ何？
Murdering little pirates.
殺人チビ海賊さ
Wonder what they're here for.
ここでいったい何してんだ
They're kinda cute.
かわいいじゃない
Ocean!
海さん
Do something! Help us!
何かして私達を助けて
The ocean doesn't help you, you help yourself!
海は助けない 自分でやるんだ
Tighten the halyard. Bind the stays!
なわを締めろ 帆を張れ
You can't sail?
できないのか
I, uh...
私...
I am self-taught.
自分で勉強しただけ
Can't you shapeshift or something?
変身できないの？
Do you see my hook?
釣り針がない
No magic hook, no magic powers!
釣り針が無いと 魔法も無し
Their boat is turning into more boats!
船が増えた
Yep, I just did that.
やっつけた
No, no!
だめ
Heihei!
ヘイヘイ
Maui!
マウイ
They took the heart!
取られた
That's a chicken.
それはニワトリ
The heart is in the...
心臓を食べた
We have to get him back!
彼を取り戻さないと
Maui!
マウイ
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
There! Right there!
そこにいる
You're turning?
方向が違う
What are you doing?
何してるの
Escaping!
逃げてるの！
The heart!
心臓が
Forget it! You'll never get it back!
もう忘れろ 取り返せない
Besides, you got a better one.
もっと良いものがある
Hey!
おいこら
What am I gonna steer with?
舵がないと...
They're just gonna kill ya!
殺されるぞ
Coconuts.
ココナッツ
Got it!
やったわ
Hey!
痛い
Yeah!
やった
We did it!
取り返した
Congratulations on not being dead, girlie.
死ななくて良かったな お嬢ちゃん
You surprise me.
驚いたよ
But I'm still not taking that thing back.
でも僕は行かないぞ
You wanna get to Te Fiti you gotta go through a whole ocean of bad.
テフィティまでは 不吉な海がある
Not to mention Te Kā.
テカーを知ってるか
Lava monster?
溶岩の怪物？
Ever defeat a lava monster?
やっつけた事あるのか？
No. Have you?
いいえ あなたは？
I'm not going on a suicide mission with some mortal.
自殺しないぞ 人間とは
You can't restore the heart without me...
僕がいないと返せない
and me says no.
僕は嫌
I'm getting my hook.
釣り針を取りに行くよ
End of discussion.
話は終わり
You'd be a hero.
あなたは英雄だった
That's what you're all about, right?
それだけ
Little girl, I am a hero.
今も英雄なの
Maybe you were.
そうかしら
But now...
今は違う
now you're just the guy who stole the heart of Te Fiti.
ただの盗っ人
The guy who cursed the world.
世界に呪いをかけた
You're no one's hero.
誰の英雄でもない
No one?
英雄ではないのか？
But...
でも
put this back...
これを返せば
save the world...
世界を救えるわ
you'd be everyone's hero.
英雄になれる
Maui! Maui! Maui!
マウイマウイ
You're so amazing!
すごーい
We'd never make it without my hook. Not past Te Kā.
釣り針がないと無理 テカーに勝てない
Then we get your hook.
それなら取りに行こう
We get your hook, take out Te Kā, restore the heart.
釣り針を取って テカーをやっつけて 心臓を返す
Unless you don't wanna be...
英雄になりたいんでしょ
Maui, demigod of the wind and sea.
風と海の半神 マウイ
Hero to...
英雄
all.
みんなの
First, we get my hook.
まず釣り針を取りに行く
Then save the world.
それから世界を救う
Deal?
のった？
Deal.
のった
Worth a shot.
ものはためしだ
Okay, we go east.
東へ行こう
To the lair of Tamatoa.
タマトアの巣へ
If anyone has my hook, it's that beady-eyed bottom-feeder.
輝く目のゴミさらいが 持ってるはず
Teach me to sail.
航海法 教えて
My job is to deliver Maui across the great ocean.
私の仕事は海を越えて マウイを運ぶ事
I should...
私は航海...
I should be sailing.
航海できないと困るの
It's called wayfinding, princess.
航海術だ お姫さん
And it's not just sails and knots...
乗って結ぶだけじゃない
it's seeing where you're going in your mind.
心で見るんだ
Knowing where you are...
今いる場所は
by knowing where you've been.
前の場所からわかる
Okay, first, I'm not a princess.
まず 私はお姫さんじゃない
I am the daughter of the chief.
村長の娘
- Same difference. - No.
同じだろ 違うわ
If you wear a dress, and you have an animal sidekick...
ドレス着て 動物を連れてりゃ
you're a princess.
お姫さんだ
You are not a wayfinder.
航海術士には
You will never be a wayfinder, you will never be a...
絶対になれない
Really? Blow dart in my butt cheek?
吹き矢?
You are a bad person.
悪党だな
If you can talk, you can teach.
話せるなら教えて
Wayfinding.
航海術の
Lesson one. Hit it.
レッスン 開始
Pull the sheet.
なわを引け
Not the sheet.
違う
No.
Nope.
それじゃない
Nope.No.
違うって
Tried that one already.
さっきやっただろ
You're measuring the stars, not giving the sky a high-five.
星を見てるんだ ハイタッチじゃないぞ
If the current's warm, you're going the right way.
潮が暖かいなら正しい
It's cold.
冷たいわ
Wait, it's getting warmer.
暖かくなった
Aah! That is disgusting! What is wrong with you?
うわっ気持ち悪い なんて事するの
We're here?
着いたの？
See, told you I could do it!
言ったでしょ
Motunui?
モトゥヌイ？
I'm home?
帰って来た？
- Moana! - Dad?
モアナ お父さん
Moana!
モアナ！
Mom?
お母さん
Help!
助けて
No!
やめて
Moana!
モアナ
Enjoy your beauty rest?
美女の眠りを楽しんだか？
You know, a real wayfinder never sleeps...
航海術士は 絶対に寝ない
so they actually get where they need to go.
目的地に着くまでは
Muscle up, buttercup.
頑張れ
We're here.
着いた
You're sure this guy's gonna have your hook?
釣り針を持ってるかしら
Tamatoa? Oh, he'll have it.
タマトアなら持ってる
He's a scavenger. Collects stuff. Thinks it makes him look cool.
ゴミあさって宝石を集めてる だからキンピカ
Ah!
おえっ
And for Tamatoa, trust me...
タマトアの事なら 信じろ
my hook is the coolest collectible.
釣り針はクールな コレクションだ
And he lives up there?
上に住んでるの？
No,no,no.
いいや
That's just the entrance...
上に入口がある
to Lalotai.
ラロタイへの
Lalotai?
ラロタイ？
Realm of monsters?
怪物の国?
We're going to the realm of monsters?
私達 怪物の国に行くの？
We? No. Me.
私達？僕だけだ
You are gonna stay here with the other chicken.
ニワトリはここで待ってろ もう一匹と
That's what I'm talking about. Gimme some.
言った事わかるかミニマウイ
Come on. That was a good one. How do you not get it?
面白い冗談だろ わからないか
I called her a chicken, there's a chicken on the boat.
彼女もニワトリって意味 もう一匹いるんだ
I know she's human, but that's not the...
彼女は人間 知ってる
You know what? Forget it. Forget it!
もういい 忘れてくれ
I'm not explaining it to you.
わからなくていい
'Cause then it's not funny.
だって面白くないから
So, daughter of the chief...
村長の娘ってのは
I thought you stayed in the village.
村にいるもんだろ
You know, kissing babies and things.
赤ちゃんにキスしたり
Hey, I'm just trying to understand...
知りたかっただけだよ
why your people decided to send...
なぜ村人は送り出したんだ？
How do I phrase this? You.
何と言うか... お前をさ
My people didn't send me.
送り出してない
The ocean did.
海が送り出した
The ocean?
海が?
Makes sense.
なるほど
You're what, eight? Can't sail.
まだ子供だろ 航海もできない
Obvious choice.
当然だな
It chose me for a reason.
きっと理由があるの
If the ocean's so smart...
もし海が賢いなら
why didn't it just take the heart back to Te Fiti itself?
なぜ自分で心臓を 取り戻さない？
Or bring me my hook?
僕に釣り針を返して くれたっていいのに
The ocean's straight up kooky-dooks.
海は賢くないんだ
But I'm sure it's not wrong about you.
お前は間違ってない
You're the Chosen One!
選ばれし者だから
The ocean chose you for a reason.
海が私を 選んだ理由があるはず
If you start singing, I'm gonna throw up.
歌ったら吐くぞ
So, not seeing an entrance.
入口がない
Yes, because it only appears...
そうさ 現れるのは
after a human sacrifice.
人間のいけにえ が要るのさ
Kidding.
冗談だよ
So serious.
本気にするな
Don't worry...
心配ない
it's a lot farther down than it looks.
見た目より ずっと深い
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
I am still falling!
まだ落ちてるー
You can do this.
私にもできる
Go!
行くわよ
And he sticks the landing.
着地
Huh?
ん?
What? Dum-dum, she's not even here.
まだ来てないのに
No mortal's gonna jump into the realm of...
人間は飛び込まないのさ
Huh?
は?
Well, she's dead.
死んだかな
Okay, let's get my hook.
釣り針を取りに行こう
Ew! Ew, ew, ew, ew.
気持ち悪い
Maui's fishhook!
マウイの釣り針
Yeah!
そのとおり
Sorry!
ごめんなさい
I thought you were a monster...
てっきり怪物だと
But I found your hook.
でも見つけた
And, you're right, this Tamatoa guy really likes his treasure.
タマトアは宝物が大好き
Stay
待ってろ
What? No. I'm the one who found...
なぜ？嫌よ私が見つけたのよ
Listen. For a thousand years...
よく聞け 千年も...
I've only been thinking of keeping this hair silky...
考え続けたのは この柔らかい髪と
getting my hook...
釣り針で...
and being awesome again.
もう一度クールになるためだ
And it's not getting screwed up by a mortal...
邪魔されたくない
who has no business inside of a monster cave, except...
怪物の洞窟で 関係ない人間に...
Except...
だけど...
maybe as bait.
エサになるなら
Huh?
は?
Wow!
おーい
The shiny, glittery cave.
きらきら輝く洞窟
And just like me...
私そっくり
it is covered in sparkly treasure.
きらめく宝物に囲まれて
Sparkle, sparkle, sparkle.
きらきら キラキラ
You're not selling it!
売ってるんじゃないぞ
This is stupid! I'm just gonna walk up and get it!
こんなの馬鹿げてる 取りに行く
You go up there, he will kill you. Just stick to the plan.
行ったら殺される 計画通りにやれ
Oh, when he shows up, keep him distracted.
やつが来たら気をそらせ
Make him talk about himself.
彼に話をさせろ
He loves bragging about how great he is.
ほめられるの大好きだから
You two must get along swell.
あなたたち仲が良いのね
No, not since I ripped off his leg.
足を もぎ取る まではな
You ripped off his...
もぎ取ったの？
Maui?
マウイ？
What have we here?
これは何だ
It's a sparkly, shiny... Wait a minute.
きらきら...光って...待てよ
Ugh! It's a human!
うわ 人間
What are you doing down here, in the realm of the...
何をしてる 怪物の国で...
Just pick an eye, babe.
選んで！
I can't concentrate on what I'm saying if you keep...
話す時に騒ぐな
Yeah, pick one, pick one!
選んで！ 選んで！
You're a funny-looking little thing, aren't you?
面白そうなこれは何
Don't! That's my gramma's!
やめて お婆さんの物！
"That's my gramma's!"
お婆さんの物
I ate my gramma!
私は自分の 婆さんを喰った
And it took a week, 'cause she was absolutely humongous.
一週間かかった 巨大だったから
Why are you here?
なぜここにいる
'Cause you're amazing!
あなたが スゴいからよ
And we mortals have heard of the tale of the crab who became a legend!
伝説のカニの話を聞いた
And I just had to know...
それに
how you became so...
あなたはとても...
crabulous?
カニっぽい
Are you just trying to get me to talk about myself?
自慢話を聞きたいのか
Because if you are...
もしお前が...
I will gladly do so.
喜んでお聞かせしよう
Huh?
は？
In song form!
歌で聞いて
Well, Tamatoa hasn't always been this glam
わしはタマトア 昔は魅力的ではなかった
I was a drab little crab once
さえない カニだった
Now I know I can be happy as a clam
でも今は超ハッピー
Because I'm beautiful, baby
美しくなったから
And did your granny say
お婆さんが言ったのかい
Listen to your heart
心の声を聞けと
Be who you are on the inside
本当の自分になれと
I need three words To tear her argument apart
その話を引き裂いてやる
Your granny lied
お前の婆さんは ウソついた
I'd rather be shiny
私はさらに輝く
Like a treasure From a sunken pirate wreck
まるで 沈んだ海賊の宝
Scrub the deck And make it look shiny
ゴシゴシ磨け ピカピカに
I will sparkle like a Wealthy woman's neck
わしはきらめく まるで首飾り
Just a sec Don't ya know
知らないと思うけど
Fish are dumb, dumb, dumb They chase anything that glitters
魚はまぬけ 光るものを追いかけて
Beginners
シロウトだよ
Oh, and here they come, come, come
やあ来た来た
To the brightest thing that glitters
最も輝く所へ
Mm, fish dinners
ふーむ シーフード
I just love free food
好きなのは フリーフード
And you look like seafood
あんたは シーフード
Hey, crab cake!
カニの肉団子
I'm back.
帰って来たぞ
It's Maui Time!
マウイの時間だ！
What do you say, little buddy?
どうするミニマウイ
Giant hawk? Coming up!
タカだな 行くぞ
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
Well, well, well.
あらあら
Little Maui's having trouble with his look
釣り針が故障
Ya little semi-demi-mini-god
小さな なんちゃって半神
Ouch What a terrible performance
ひどい 出来だ
Get the hook Get it?
釣り針を握ったか
You don't swing it Like you used to, man
昔みたいに行かないぞ
Yet I have to give you Credit for my start
あんたのおかげで始めたよ
And your tattoos on the outside
入れ墨のマネをして
For just like you I made myself a work of art
自分を芸術品にした
I'll never hide I can't
隠れはしない 出来ないんだ
I'm too shiny
ピカピカだから
Watch me dazzle Like a diamond in the rough
目がくらむだろ 磨けば光るさ
Strut my stuff My stuff is so shiny
見せびらかすのさ 輝きを
Send your armies But they'll never be enough
大勢でも勝てないぞ
My shell's too tough Maui, man
私の殻は固いぞ マウイよ
You can try, try, try But you can't expect a demigod
頑張れ 半神にはガッカリ
To beat a decapod Look it up
十本足にはかなわない
You Will die, die, die
お前は死ぬ
Now it's time for me to take apart
そろそろ時間だ
Your achin' heart
お前の心臓をバラバラに
Far from the ones who abandoned you
人間は お前を見捨てた
Chasing the love of these humans
人間の愛を欲しがった
Who made you feel wanted
人気者の気分だった
You tried to be tough
強くなりたくても
But your armor's just not hard enough
お前の皮膚は強くない
Maui Now it's time to kick your heinie
マウイ 蹴飛ばすぞ
Ever seen someone so shiny
こんなに輝くやつ 見た事ないだろ
Soak it in 'Cause it's the last you'll ever see
最後だからよく見ろ
C'est la vie Mon ami
サヨナラ わが友
I'm so shiny
私はピカピカ
Now I eat you so prepare your final plea
喰うぞ 祈って準備しろ
Just for me
私のために
You'll never be quite as shiny
お前はあんまり光ってない
You wish you were nice and shiny
ピカピカだったら良かったね
- Hey! - Huh?
ねえ！ なに?
I got something shiny for ya!
ピカピカの あげるわ！
The heart of Te Fiti.
テフィティの心臓
You can't run from me!
逃げられないぞ
Oh, you can. You keep surprising me.
逃げるのか ビックリだな
There's only so far you can get on those two little legs.
二本足じゃ 逃げられないぞ
The power of creation...
生命の源
for a crustacean.
甲殻類のな
Where is it? Where is it?
どこへ行った
We gotta go!
逃げないと
What about the heart?
心臓どうすんだよ
He can have it. I've got a better one.
いいのよ もっと良いのがある
Yes, I have the...
見つけたぞ
Wait a minute.
ちょっと待った
I see, she's taken a barnacle and she's covered it in...
これはフジツボ 表面は
bioluminescent algae as a diversion.
光る藻で覆われ 気をそらすための...
Come back here!
戻って来い
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
Hey!
ところで
Did you like the song?
歌は良かった？
We're alive!
生きてた！
Listen...
聞け
I appreciate what you did down there.
ありがとよ 海底で
Mm-hmm.
うーん
- Took guts. - Mm-hmm.
勇敢だった... うん
- But“ - Mm-hmm.
でも... うんうん
I'm sorry.
こら
I'm trying to be sincere for once, and it feels like you're distracted.
素直に言ってんだ ちゃんと聞け
No, no. No way!
ちゃんと聞いてない？ 聞いてるわ
Really? Because you're looking at me like I have a...
言いたそうな顔だ 僕がまるで
shark head.
サメ頭だって
What? Do you have a shark head?
えっ サメ頭だったの
Look, the point is...
言いたかったのは
for a little girl, child, thing, whatever...
小さな女の子が まあいい...
who had no business being down there...
関係ないのに
you did me a solid.
手を貸してくれた
But you also almost died.
死ぬ所だったんだぞ
And I couldn't even beat that dumb crab.
僕はカニさえ 倒せなかった
So, chances of beating Te Kā?
テカーを倒せるもんか
Bupkis.
だめだ
We're never making it to Te Fiti. This mission is cursed.
テフィティに行けない 呪われてる
It's not cursed.
呪われてない
Shark head.
サメ頭
It is not cursed.
呪わていない
Cursed.
呪われてる
What can I say except
言うかしないよ
We're dead soon
もうすぐ死ぬんだ
Can you at least try?
試しても見ないの？
Giant hawk.
大きなタカ
Hey, it's okay, it's okay We're dead soon
いいんだ もうすぐ死ぬから
All right, break time's over.
休み時間は終わり
Get up.
起きて
Why? Are you gonna give me a speech?
演説するのか
Tell me I can beat Te Ka 'cause I'm "Maui?"
テカーを倒せると？ 僕がマウイだから？
Take a hike, Tiny.
消えなミニマウイ
How do you get your tattoos?
この入れ墨は？
They show up. When I earn them.
勝手に現れたんだ
How'd you earn that one? What's that for?
どうして
That's man's discovery of Nunya.
物語さ
What's Nunya?
何の？
Nunya business.
関係ないだろ
I'll just keep asking.
聞き続けるわ
What's it for?
何が書いてあるの
You need to stop doing that.
やめてくれよ
- Back off. - Just tell me what it is.
やめてくれよ じゃ教えて
I said back off.
やめろったら
Is it why your hook's not working?
釣り針の調子が悪いから？
You don't wanna talk, don't talk.
教えたくないなら 言わなくていい
You wanna throw me off the boat...
私を投げたいなら
throw me off.
投げてもいい
You wanna tell me I don't know what I'm doing...
言いたいんでしょ 私が 自分で何してるのわかってないって
I know I don't.
わかってないって 知ってるわ
I have no idea why the ocean chose me.
なぜ私が選ばれたのか わからない
You're right.
あなたは正しい
But my island is dying...
でも島が死にかけている
so I am here.
だからここにいる
It's just me and you.
私とあなただけ
And I want to help...
みんなを助けたい
but I can't if you don't let me.
あなたがいないと助けられない
I wasn't born a demigod.
生まれた時 半神じゃなかった
I had human parents.
両親は人間
They took one look and decided...
僕を少し見て決めた
they did not want me.
要らないって
They threw me into the sea...
僕を海に捨てた
like I was nothing.
平気で
Somehow, I was found by the gods.
ともかく神様が 僕を見つけてくれた
They gave me the hook.
魔法の釣り針をくれた
They made me...
僕は半神の...
Maui.
マウイになった
And back to the humans I went.
人間の所に帰ったよ
I gave them islands, fire, coconuts.
僕は人間に与えた 島や火やココナッツを
Anything they could ever want.
欲しがる物は何でも
You took the heart for them.
心から尽くしたのね
You did everything for them.
あなたは何でもした
So they'd love you.
だから人間はあなたを愛したはず
It was never enough.
足りなかったんだ
Maybe the gods found you for a reason.
神様があなたを見つけたのは 理由があった
Maybe the ocean brought you to them...
海が神様に届けたのも
because it saw someone who was worthy of being saved.
救う価値があると思ったから
But the gods aren't the ones who make you Maui.
あなたをマウイにした神様とは 違うけど...
You are.
あなたも神様でしょ
Okay, Okay-
よしよし
I love you, too, buddy.
大好きだミニマウイ
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
Yeah!
その調子
Next stop, Te Fiti.
テフィティに行こう
What?
なによ
I figured it out.
わかったんだ
You know, the ocean used to love when I pulled up islands...
僕が島を作ると 海はいつも愛してくれた
'cause your ancestors would sail her seas and find 'em.
先祖が航海して 島を見つけたから
All those new lands, new villages.
新しい島に 新しい村ができた
It was the water that connected 'em all.
海がみんなを 結びつけてるって事をさ
And if I were the ocean...
もし僕が 海だったら きっと探す
I think I'd be looking for a curly-haired non-princess...
ちぢれ髪で お姫さんでない人を
to start that again.
再びみんなを 結びつける時に
That is literally the nicest thing you've ever said to me.
一番いい事言った
Probably should have saved it for Te Fiti.
でもテフィティのために取っておいて
I did.
そうしたさ
Moana of Motunui...
モトゥヌイのモアナ
I believe you have officially delivered Maui across the great sea.
正式にマウイを 海を越えて運んだ
Moana! Moana! Moana!
モアナ！モアナ！
You're so amazing!
すごーい
It's time.
いよいよだ
Go save the world.
世界を救って
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
Maui!
マウイ
What are you doing?
何をする
Finding you a better way in!
もっと良い入口を探すの
- We won't make it! - Yes, we will!
無理だ 大丈夫よ
- Turn around! - No!
引き返せ だめよ
Moana, stop!
モアナ やめるんだ
No!
嫌よ
Are you okay?
大丈夫?
Maui?
マウイ？
I told you to turn back.
引き返せと言ったのに
I thought we could make it.
私達 できると思ったのよ
We?
私達？
I thought I could make it.
私が...できると思った
We can fix it.
直せる？
It was made by the gods.
神様が作ったんだぞ
You can't fix it!
直せないよ
Next time we'll be more careful.
次はもっと気をつける
Te Kā was stuck on the barrier islands.
テカーは 囲い島から動けない
It's lava, it can't go in the water.
溶岩だから 海に入れない
We can find a way around.
回り道をすればきっと入れる
I'm not going back.
戻らないぞ
We still have to restore the heart.
心臓を返さないと
My hook is cracked.
釣り針が ひび割れた
One more hit, and it's over.
あと一撃でおしまいだ
Maui, you have to restore the heart.
マウイ心臓を返して
Without my hook, I am nothing.
釣り針がないと 僕はダメだ
That's not true!
そんな事ない
Without my hook, I am nothing!
釣り針がないと 僕はダメなんだ
We are only here...
私達がここにいるのは
because you stole the heart in the first place.
あなたが盗んだからよ
No, we're here because the ocean told you you're special...
海が言ったからだろ お前が特別だって
and you believed it.
お前は信じた
I am Moana of Motunui.
私はモアナ モトゥヌイの...
- You will board my boat... - Goodbye, Moana.
私の船に乗り... じゃあなモアナ
...sail across the sea...
海を越え...
I'm not killing myself...
死にたくないんだ
so you can prove you're something you're not!
特別じゃないって 証明してくれ
...and restore the heart of Te Fiti!
テフィティの心臓を 返しなさい
The ocean chose me!
海が選んだの
It chose wrong.
海が間違えたんだ
Maui!
マウイ
Why did you bring me here?
なぜ私を ここに連れて来たの
I'm not the right person.
私じゃない
You have to choose someone else.
他の人を選んで
Choose someone else.
Please.
お願い
No.
You're a long ways past the reef.
珊瑚礁からずいぶん 遠くへ来たね
Gramma?
お婆さん？
Guess I chose the right tattoo.
私の入れ墨は間違ってなかった
Gramma!
お婆さん！
I tried, Gramma.
私 努力したの
I couldn't do it.
出来なかった
It's not your fault.
お前は悪くない
I never should have put so much on your shoulders.
こんな重荷を背負わせるべきではなかった
If you are ready to go home...
家に帰るのなら
I will be with you.
一緒に帰ろう
Why do you hesitate?
迷っているのかい
I don't know.
わからない
I know a girl from an island
島から来た少女は
She stands apart from the crowd
みんなと違った
She loves the sea and her people
海と民を愛し
She makes her whole family proud
家族の誇り
Sometimes the world seems against you
ときには世界が立ちはだかる
The journey may leave a scar
旅は傷跡を残すだろう
But scars can heal and reveal just
傷跡は癒えて教えてくれる
Where you are
あなたのいる場所を
The people you love will change you
愛する人々が あなたを変える
The things you have learned will guide you
学んだ事が あなたを導く
And nothing on earth can silence
地上のすべては 静かではない
The quiet voice still inside you
静かな声は あなたの中に
And when that voice starts to whisper
その声がささやき始めて
Moana, you've come so far
モアナ ここまで来た
Moana, listen
モアナ 聞いて
Do you know who you are?
あなたは誰
Who am I?
私は誰
I am a girl who loves my island
私は島を愛する少女
And the girl who loves the sea
そして海を愛する少女
It calls me
海は私を呼ぶ
I am the daughter of the village chief
私は村長の娘
We are descended from voyagers
航海者の子孫
Who found their way across the world
世界中の航路を知る
They call me
彼らが呼ぶ
I've delivered us to where we are
ここまでやって来た
I have journeyed farther
より遠くへ旅をした
I am everything I've learned and more
学び私のすべてになった もっと学ぶ
Still it calls me
今も海は私を呼ぶ
And the call isn't out there at all
外ではなく
It's inside me
私の中で
It's like the tide
潮の流れのよう
Always falling and rising
いつも上がったり下がったり
I will carry you here in my heart
心の中にあなたがいる
You remind me
あなたは教えてくれる
That come what may
何が起ころうと
I know the way
道がわかると
I am Moana
私はモアナ
I am Moana of Motunui.
私はモトゥヌイのモアナ
Aboard my boat...
船に乗って
I will sail across the sea...
海を越え...
and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
私が テフィティの心臓を返す
Te Kā can't follow us into the water.
テカーは海まで 追いかけてこない
We make it past the barrier islands...
囲い島を越えて
we make it to Te Fiti.
テフィティに行ける
None of which you understand...
わからなくていい
because you are a chicken.
ニワトリだから
No!
待って
Heihei! No, no, no!
ヘイヘイ 待って
Nice work!
やるじゃない
Te Fiti.
テフィティ
Maui!
マウイ
You came back.
戻ってきてくれた
But your hook.
でも釣り針は
One more hit and...
あと一回で...
Te Kai's gotta catch me first.
テカーに 捕まらなけりゃいいんだろ
I got your back, Chosen One.
任せろ選ばれし者
Go save the world.
世界を救え
Maui.
マウイ
Thank you.
ありがとう
You're welcome.
どういたしまして
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
Hot-hot-hot, hot-hot-hot!
あちち
Hey, Te Kā!
おいテカー
Shark head!
サメ頭だぞ
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
Moana!
モアナ
Get the heart to the spiral!
心臓を うず巻きに
Te Fiti...
テフィティ...
it's gone.
いない
Te Kā!
テカー
Let her come to me.
私の所へ 来させて
I have crossed the horizon to find you
あなたを見つけに 水平線を越えた
I know your name
あなたの名前を知ってる
They have stolen the heart from inside you
あなたの心臓が盗まれた
But this does not define you
それで決まる訳ではない
This is not who you are
本当のあなたではない
You know who you are
あなたは自分が誰なのか 知っている
Who you truly are.
本当は誰なのか
Te Fiti!
テフィティ
The chicken lives.
生きてた
I'm sorry about your hook.
釣り針は残念
Well, hook, no hook...
釣り針がなくたって
I'm Maui.
僕はマウイさ
Te Fiti!
テフィティ
Hey, I mean, how you been?
よう元気だったか
Look, what I did was...
僕がした事は...
wrong.
間違ってた
I have no excuse.
言い訳はない
I'm sorry.
すまない
You know, it'd be rude to refuse a gift from a goddess.
断らないで プレゼントよ
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
Thank you.
ありがとう
Your kind gesture is deeply appreciated.
親切に深く感謝
Cheeeehoooo.
チーホー
Gonna miss you, drumstick.
寂しくなる  やせっぽっち
You could come with us, you know.
一緒に来ればいいのに
My people are going to need a master wayfinder.
航海術の達人が必要なの
They already have one.
一人いるだろ すでに
See you out there, Maui.
またね マウイ
See you out there, Moana.
それじゃな モアナ
Cheeeehoooo!
チーホー
Mom! Dad!
お母さん お父さん
Moana!
モアナ！
I may have gone a little ways past the reef.
珊瑚礁の向こうに ちょっと行っちゃったかも
It suits you.
お前らしいな
She's back!
帰って来た
Moana!
モアナ
Pua!
プア
Moana!
モアナ
Welcome home!
おかえりなさい
We set a course to find
航路を定め
A brand new island everywhere we roam
新しい島を見つける 我らはさすらう
We keep our island in our mind
島の場所を知ってる
And when it's time to find home We know the way
帰る時は道がわかる
We are explorers reading every sign
我らは探検家 どんなサインも読み取る
We tell the stories of our elders In a never-ending chain
果てしない先祖の伝説
We know the way
道がわかる
Japanese subtitles : Jo
日本語字幕 JO
Shiny
ピカピカ
I'm so shiny
私はピカピカ
Didn't help me though, did it?
助けてくれなかった
Still upside down here.
ずっとここで逆さま
Just need a little push.
ちょっと押してくれ
Can we be real?
本当なの？
If my name was Sebastian and I had a cool Jamaican accent...
もし名前がセバスチャンで クールなジャマイカ訛りだったら
you'd totally help me.
助けてくれたよな
You would. You know you would.
絶対に